Guide to the Pavel Tchelitchew Collection
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Photographs and Other Papers, 1907-1970; Series IV; 0.83; (2 boxes)
  - Photographs
    - Beaton, Cecil, undated (Box 27, Folder 445a)
    - Chelishchev family in Russia, 1907-1928 (Box 27, Folder 446-447)
    - Crevel, Rene, undated (Box 27, Folder 448)
    - De Lasteyrie, Louis, undated (Box 27, Folder 449)
    - Diaghilev, Serge, 1929, 1954 (Box 27, Folder 450)
      Contains: Photographs of death mask and photographs of a 1954 Diaghliev exhibit.
    - Doubrovska, Felia, 1931, undated
    - Errante, New York production, undated
    - Ford, Charles Henri, undated (Box 27, Folder 451)
      Includes portraits by Carl Van Vechten and Cecil Beaton.
    - Gorer, Geoffrey, undatd (Box 27, Folder 451a)
    - Karsavina, Tamara, 1933 (Box 27, Folder 451b)
    - Markevitch, Igor, undated (Box 27, Folder 452)
      See also: Tchelitchew, Pavel
      Includes Roger Ford.
    - Nabokov, [Mrs.], undated (Box 27, Folder 452a)
    - Nabokov, Nicolas, 1935-1936 (Box 27, Folder 452b)
    - Paley, Natalie, undated (Box 27, Folder 452c)
    - Parisot, _____ ("Mère"), undated (Box 27, Folder 453)
      See also: Tchelitchew, Pavel and Zaoussailoff, Alexandra
    - Rubenstein, Helena, undated (Box 27, Folder 453a)
    - Rumnev, Aleksandr, 1923, undated (Box 27, Folder 454)
      Includes Zinaida Torkhovskaia.
    - Sassoon, Siegfried, undated (Box 27, Folder 455)
      See also: Tennant, Stephen
    - Sitwell, Edith, 1928, undated (Box 27, Folder 456)
      Includes photographs by Cecil Beaton.
    - Stein, Gertrude, undated (Box 27, Folder 457)
      Includes a photograph by Man Ray of Picasso's portrait of Stein.
    - [Szold, Bernardine?], undated (Box 27, Folder 458)
    - Tanner, Allen, undated (Box 27, Folder 459)
    - Tchelitchew, Pavel, 1923-1956 (Box 27, Folder 460-464)
      Includes photographs of Tchelitchew and of paintings by Tchelitchew.
      Includes _____ Brotzky, Natalia Glasko, Geoffrey and Peter Gorer, Youra Grab_____, [Allanah] Harper, Igor Markevitch, "Mère" Parisot, Klemente Redko, Edith Sitwell, Jacques Stettiner, Allen Tanner, Peter Watson, and Alexandra Zaoussailoff.
    - Tchelitchew, Pavel, portraits by Cecil Beaton, undated
    - Tchelitchew, Pavel, portraits by George Platt Lynes, undated
    - Tchelitchew, Pavel, portrait by [A. Ortier?], undated
    - Tennant, Stephen, 1934, undated (Box 27, Folder 465)
      Includes Siegfried Sassoon.
    - Tyler, Parker, photographs by Carl Van Vechten, 1935 (Box 27, Folder 465a)
    - Vincent, Charles, 1931 (Box 27, Folder 466)
    - Watson, Peter, 1933 (Box 27, Folder 467)
    - Welles, Orson, undated (Box 27, Folder 467a)
    - Wheeler, Monroe, portrait by George Platt Lynes, undated
    - Zaoussailoff, Alexandra, 1921-1970 (Box 27, Folder 468)
      Includes Raoul Leven, "Mère" Parisot and Allen Tanner.
    - Unidentified, 1941-1954, undated (Box 27, Folder 469-470)
    - Notes on photographs in Pavel Tchelitchew's hand, undated
  - Other material
    - Tchelitchew's engagement books, 1929-1931 (Box 27, Folder 471-473)
    - Tchelitchew's engagement books, 1932-1950 (Box 28, Folder 474-477)
    - Tchelitchew's diaries, undated (Box 28, Folder 478-480)
    - Official documents, 1917-1940 (Box 28, Folder 481-482)
      Includes Tchelitchew's passport, attestation of nobility, and secondary school and military service certificates.
    - Christmas card list, 1955 (Box 28, Folder 483)
    - Pencil sketch of two costumes for an unidentified production, undated (Box 28, Folder 484)
    - Drawing of a costume for Aleko, 1922
    - Prop leaves from the set of Ondine, cloth, circa 1939 (Box 28, Folder 485)
    - Audio recording [of Pavel Tchelitchew?], undated (Box 28, Folder 486)
    - Cast of [Pavel Tchelitchew's?] hands, undated (Box 28a)
- Oversize, 4.02; (3 boxes)
  - Catalogs and announcements for exhibits of Tchelitchew's art (Series III), 1927, 1964 (Box 29, Folder 487)
  - Programs for theater and ballet performances (Series III), 1921-1939 (Box 29, Folder 488-495)
  - "Influences" (Series III), 1923-1936, undated (Box 29, Folder 496-499)
  - Clippings (Series III), 1920s-1960s (Box 29, Folder 500-503)
  - Serial publications on art and theater (Series III), 1921-1962 (Box 29, Folder 504-505)
  - Monographs on art and theater, some inscribed to Tchelitchew (Series III), 1934, 1956 (Box 29, Folder 506)
  - Drawing of a costume for Aleko (Series IV), 1922 (Box 29, Folder 507)
  - Broadside for Ondine (Series III), 1939 (Box 508)
  - Guest register for an exhibit of Tchelitchew's art (Series III), 1956 (Box 31, Folder 517)
  - Abdy, L. (Series IV), undated (Box 31, Folder 518)
  - Diaghliev exhibit (Series IV), 1954 (Box 31, Folder 519)
  - Doubrovska, Felia (Series IV), undated (Box 31, Folder 520)
  - Errante, New York production (Series IV), undated (Box 31, Folder 521)
  - Ford, Charles Henri, portraits by Cecil Beaton (Series IV), undated (Box 31, Folder 522)
  - Sitwell, Edith, portraits by Cecil Beaton (Series IV), undated (Box 31, Folder 523)
  - Tennant, Stephen (Series IV), 1934 (Box 31, Folder 524)
  - Tchelitchew, Pavel, photograph of a portrait (painting) of Mme. Gorer (Series IV), undated (Box 31, Folder 525)
  - Tchelitchew, Pavel, photographs of him painting (Series IV), undated (Box 31, Folder 526)
  - Tchelitchew, Pavel, portraits by Cecil Beaton (Series IV), undated (Box 32, Folder 527-528)
  - Tchelitchew, Pavel, portraits by George Platt Lynes (Series IV), undated (Box 32, Folder 529)
  - Tchelitchew, Pavel, portrait by [A. Ortier?] (Series IV), undated (Box 32, Folder 530)
  - Wheeler, Monroe, portrait by George Platt Lynes, undated (Box 32, Folder 531)
  - Unidentified (Series IV), undated (Box 32, Folder 532-534)
  - Notes on photographs in Pavel Tchelitchew's hand (Series IV), undated (Box 32, Folder 535)
- Restricted Fragile, 0.42; (1 box)
  Conditions Governing Access
  Restricted fragile material. Reference surrogates have been substituted in the main files. For further information consult the appropriate curator.
  - Series I. Correspondence (Box 30, Folder 509-510)
  - Series II. Writings (Box 30, Folder 511-515)
  - Series III. Printed Material (Box 30, Folder 516)